Evening star is shining bright,
So make a wish and hold on tight,
There's magic in the air tonight,
And anything can happen.
Just in that moment,
the ugly little frog
looked up with his sad,
round eyes and pleaded:
Oh, please, dear princess,
Only a kiss from you
can break this terrible spell,
that was inflicted on me
by a wicked witch.
There comes my favorite part.
And the beautiful princess
was so moved by his desperate plea,
that she stooped down,
picked up the slippery creature,
leaned forward,
raised him to her lips,
and kissed that little frog.
Than the frog was transformed
into a handsome prince.
They were married and lived
happily ever after.
The end.
Yay! Read it again, read it again!
Sorry Charlotte,it's time for us
to be headin' home.
Say good night, Tiana.
There is no way,
in this whole wide world ...
I would ever, ever, ever I mean never
kiss a frog. Yuck!
Is that so?
Here comes your prince charming, Tia.
Come on, kiss.
- No! Yes, Yes!
- Stop it!
- I won't, I won't, I won't!
- I would do it.
I would kiss a frog.
I would kiss a hundred frogs,
if I could marry a prince
and be a princess.
You girls, stop tormentin'
that poor little kitty.
Poor little thing.
- Evenin' Eudora!
- Daddy, Daddy, look at my new dress.
- Isn't it pretty?
- Hah,hah,  look at you. Why, I'd expect nothin' less
from the finest seamstress in New Orleans.
Uuh, I want that dress.
- Oh, no sugar come on.
- I want that one.
- Please, please, please, please!
- Eudora.
You suppose you can
web something up like that ?
- Anything for my best customer.
- Yeah!
Come along, Tiana.
Your Dad should be home from work by now.
Aah,now princess,you gettin'
that drift but that's it.
No more Mr. Pushover.
- Now who wants a puppy?
- I do! I do! He's so cute!
Mmm, gumbo smells good Tiana.
- I think it's done, Daddy.
- Yeah. Are you sure? -Mm-hmm.
- Absolutely positive?
- Yes!
Okay, I'm about to put
this spoon in my ...
-Wait!
-Done.
- What?
- Well, sweetheart ...
This is the...
The best gumbo I've ever tasted.
Come here. Eudora, our little girl's got a gift.
- I coulda have told you that.
- A gift this special
just gotta be shared.
Hey everybody I made gumbo.
Uuuh, that's smells good
You know the thing about good food?
It brings folks together from all walks of life.
It warms them right up and it
puts little smiles on their faces.
And when I open up my own restaurant,
I tell you, people are gonna lined up
for miles around,
just to get a taste of my food.
- Our food!
- That's right, baby.
Our food.
- Daddy, look.
- Where're you goin'?
Charlotte's faity tale book said,
if you make a wish on evening star
it shoulda come true.
- Hmmh, won't you wish on that star, sweetheart?
- Yes, you wish and you dream
with all your little heart.
But you remember dear anawet,
that old star can only take you part of a way.
You got to help him with some hard work of your own.
And then...
Yeah you can do anything
you said you mind to.
Just promise your Daddy one thing?
That you'll  never, ever lose sign
what is really important.
Okay?
See you in the morning, baby cakes.
Get some sleep.
Please, please, please.
Aaaaaaah!!!
Well Miss Tiana rough night for tips
but every little penny counts.
Don't you worry, Daddy ...
We'll be there soon.
Goodnight Cal's,
good morning Duke's.
In the South Land
there's a city
Way down on the river
Where the women are very pretty
And all the men deliver
They got music it's always playin'
Start in the day time
go all through the night
when you hear that music playin'
Hear what I'm saying and make it feel alright
Grab somebody, come on down
Bring your paintbrush, we're painting the town
Oh there's some sweetness going around
Catch it down in New Orleans
We got magic, good and mase
Make it happen, make it real, say
If anything you want is lose what you have
Down here in New Orleans
Hey partner,
don't be shy
Come on down here and give us a try
You wanna do some livin' before you die
Do it down in New Orleans
Stalee homes and mansions
Of the sugar darns and cotton candy
Rich people, old people, all got dreams ...
Dreams do come true in New Orleans.
Order up!
- Another coffee here, sug' .
- Comin' right up, Virgil.
- Hey, Tiana
- Morning, Georgia.
- Hi, how are you doin' Tiana?
- Hey y'all!
- We all goin' out dancin' tonight. Care to join us?
- Yeah, c'mon, Tiana, you could use a little hand. It's Mardi Gras.
No, I got two left feet. Besides I'm gonna...
You need a napkin, sweetheart?
I'm gonna work a double shift tonight...
Here you are, cakes.
- You know, so I...
- You can save for your restaurant.
I know, I know.
Girl! All you ever do is work!
Order up!
- Maybe next time.
I told y'all she wouldn't come.
- Are you talkin' 'bout that dang restaurant again?
- Buford, your eggs are burnin'.
- You ain't never gonna get enough for the dang payment.
- I'm gettin' close.
- Yeah. How close?
- Where my flapjacks?
Hah, hah!You got about as much chance
of gettin' that restaurant
as I do of winnin' the Kentucky Derby.
Saddle me up, y'all and pump that...
- Mornin', Mr. La Bouff.
- Good mornin', Tiana.
Congratulations on bein' voted
king of the Mardi Gras parade.
Caught me completely by surprise
... for the fifth year in a row.
- Now, how about I celebrate with...
- Beignets?
Got me a fresh batch just waitin' for you.
Well, keep 'em comin' 'til I pass out.
- Oh Tia! Tia, Tia, Tia!!
- Charlotte?! -Did you get the news?
Tell her, oh tell her Big Daddy.
- Oh, yeah. Prince Naveen ...
- Prince Naveen of Maldonia is coming to New Orleans.
Isn't it the bee's knees?
Tell her what you did, Big Daddy.
Tell her!
- Well, I invited ...
- Daddy invited the prince to a masquerade.Volcanized!
Tell her what else you did Big Daddy.
Go on.
- And he stay...
- And he stay ...
And he stay in our house
as my personal guest.
Oh, Lottie, that's swell.
A little worthy advice:
My Mom always said that the quicks way
to a man's heart is through his stomach.
- That's it.
- What just happend?
Oh, Tia, you are Bonafide genius.
I'm gonna need about five hundred
of your man-catching beignets
for my ball tonight.
Let's get it Daddy.
Will this many cover it?
Well? This should cover it just fine, Lottie.
This is it!
I'm gettin' my restaurant.
Tonight my prince is
finally coming.
And I'll show his happy and not let him go.
FENNER BROS. REALTY
FOR SALE
Everything looks pita pa key , Mr Fenner.
- And. .. Mr Fenner.
- We have all the paperwork ready to sign,
- for this thing at Mardi Gras .
- I do you one better,
why we don't sign tonight when i see you
all at the La Bouff masquerade ball.
You got the whole bargain, Tiana.
- Table for one, please.
- Oh, Mama.
Here is  a little something to..
help you get started.
Daddy's gumbo pot.
I know.
I miss him too.
Well now...
Hurry up and open the door.
Just look at it, Mama.
Doesn't just make you wanna cry?
Yes.
The main D. gonna be right where you are stayin'.
And over here, a gourmande kitchen.
And hang up from the ceiling
a big, old crystal chandelier.
You are your Daddy's daughter, all right.
He used to go on and on about
this old sugar mill too.
Baby cakes, I'm sure, this place
is gonna be just wonderful.
But it's a shame you're working so hard.
But how can I let it now
when I'm so close.
I got to make sure all that
hard work means something.
Tiana!
Your Daddy may not have gotten place you always wanted
but he had something better.
He had love.
And that's all I want
for you, sweetheart.
To me you and prince charming
end dance out until y'all happily ever after.
I don't have time for dancing.
That's just gonna have to wait a while
How long we're talkin' about here?
Ain't got time for messing around
And it's not my style
I want some grandkids.
This whole town can slow you down
People taking the easy way
But I know exactly where I'm going
And getting closer, closer, every day
And I'm almost there
I'm almost there
People down here think I'm crazy,
but I don't care
Tribes and tribulations
have had my share
There ain't nothing gonna stop me now
cause I'm almost there
I remember Daddy told me :
Fairytales can come true
You gotta make 'em happen
it all depends on you
So I work real hard each and every day
Now things for sure are going my way
Just doing what I do
Look out boys I'm coming through
And I'm almost there
I'm almost there
People gonna come here from everywhere
And I'm almost there,
I'm almost there
There's been tribes and tribulations
You know I've had my share
But I've climbed the mountain,
I've crossed the river
And I'm almost there,
I'm almost there
I'm almost there !
- Excuse me!
- You need a hand in there, buddy?
Achedanza... (Cool)
Sira ... I've been looking for you
everywhere.
What a coincidence, Lawrence.
I've been avoiding you everywhere.
- We are going to be late for the Masquerade.
- Listen, Lawrence, listen.
It's jazz, that's the music.
It was born here.
It's beautiful, no?
No.
Oh, dance with me, fat man.
Get loose, Lawrence.
- We supposed to be at La Bouff's estate by now.
- Yes, yes, yes. But first ...
I buy everyone here a drink.
With what?
At this point you have
two choices:
Woo and marry richa lady or ...
Get a job.
All right, fine but first...
We dance.
- This is idiocy.
- For someone who can't see his feet,
you're very light on them!
It's perfect. You're finally getting
into the music!
Do you get my joke?
Because your head is, it is in the tuba!
- Get me out!
- All right.Hold on.
Degrading. I never been
so humiliated.
Hello?
Gentlemen.
Enchantée.
A tip of the hat from Dr. Facilier.
How y'all doin'?
Tarot readings, charms, potions ...
Dreams made real!
- Achedanza! (Cool)
- Were I a betting man...And I'm not,
- I stay away from games of chance...
- Sira! - I'd wager...
I'm in the company of visiting royalty.
Lawrence, Lawrence!
This remarkable gentleman
has just read my palm!
Or this morning's newspaper?
Sira, this chap is obviosuly a  charlatan.
- I suggest we move on to a less...
- Don't you disrespect me little man!.
Don't you derogate or deride!
You're in my world now, Not your world
And I've got friends on the other side!
He's got friends on the other side...
That's just an echo, gentlemen. Just a little
somethin' we have here in Louisiana,
a little parlor trick. Don't worry....
Sit down at my table
Put your minds at ease
If you relax it will enable me to do
anything I please
I can read your future
I can change it 'round some, too
I'll look deep into your heart and soul
(you do have a soul, don't you, Lawrence?)
Make your wildest dreams come true!
I got voodoo, I got hoodoo,
I got things I ain't even tried!
And I got friends on the other side.
He's got friends on the other side...
The cards, the cards, the cards will tell
The past, the present, and the future
as well
The cards, the cards,
just take three
Take a little trip into your future with me!
Now you, young man, are from across the sea
You come from two long lines of royalty
(I'm a royal myself on my mother's side)
Your lifestyle's high
But your funds are low
You need to marry a little honey
whose daddy got dough
Mommy and daddy cut you off, huh playboy?
-Yeah, sad but true.
Now y'all gotta get hitched,
but hitchin' ties you down.
You just wanna be free.
Hop from place to place.
But freedom... takes green!
It's the green, it's the green,
it's the green you need
And when I looked into your future
It's the green that I see!
On you little man,
I don't want to waste much time
You been pushed around all your life
You been pushed around by your mother
and your sister and your brother.
And if you was married...
You'd be pushed around by your wife
But in your future, the you I see
It's exactly the man you always wanted to be!
Shake my hand.
Come on, boys
Won't you shake the poor sinner's hand?
-Are you ready?
-Transformation central!
-Reformation central!
Transmogrification central!
Can you feel it?
You're changin', You're changin'
You're changin', all right!
I hope you're satisfied
But if you ain't
Don't blame me
You can blame my friends on the other side!
You got what you wanted!
But you lost what you had!
Hush...
Ah, Senator Johnson!
Hey, Jimmy.
I hope you leavin' some of the beignets
so you can stich once.
No, pipe and hot.
Stella, excuse me...
Stella, no, no.
Okay, but just one.
But Miss Charlotte ...
You said later two hours?
Travis! When a woman says later,
she really means not ever!
Now run along.
There are plenty of young fillies
dyin' for you to waltz them into a stupor.
- Gimme that napkins! Quick!
- What on earth for?
I swear, I'm sweatin' like a sinner in church!
- Oh, Tia, is gettin' to be so late.
- There's still a few straglers.
This is a failure. Tia, my prince is never comin'.
- Now, Lottie...
- I never get anything I wish for!
Lottie, wait!
- Just calm down and take a deep...
- Maybe I just got to wish harder.
Please, please, please
please, please ...
Lottie, you can't just wish
on a star expecting ...
Ladies and gentlemen!
His Royal Highness,
Prince Naveen.
Good Evening, Tiana.
Marvelous party.
Evening, Mr. Fenner.
And. .. Mr. Fenner.
- I'm smelling meanies.
- Gonna be the House specialty,
once I signed those papers
you're brought.
-Yes ...
-About that...
- You were outbid.
- What?
The fella came in offering
a full amount of cash.
Less you can tap his offer
by Wendesday.
You can kiss that place goodbye.
You know how long it took
me to save that money?
Exactly! Which is why a
little woman of your background ...
woulda had a hands full,trying to run
a big business like that.
You better off, will y'all,  yeah!
- No, wait a minute!
- No more meanies, no!
No. .. hold on a minute!
You..you come back!
Tia, time to get prince
charmed with those man-catchin' beign...
- What happend?
- I. .. I ...just.
Oh, you poor dear. Oh, Prince Naveen,
We will be right back, sugar.
I got just a dress for you.
Oh, Tia, honey, did you see the way
he danced with me?
A marriage proposal,
can be far behind.
Thank you, Evening star!
You know, I was taught to think
that wishing on stars was just for...
Babies an' crazy people.
Look at you!
Aren't you just as pretty as
a magnolia in May?
Seems like only yesterday
we were ...
Both little girls, dreaming
our fairy tales dreams.
And tonight they're finally coming true!
Well...back into the fray!
Wish me luck.
Oh,  Naveen ...
Almost...
Almost there
People would come here from everywhere
I was almost...
There.
I can not believe I'm doing this.
Please... Please... Please!
Very funny.
So, what now?
I reckon you want a kiss?
Kissing would be nice, yes?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I did not mean to scare you, I...
Wait, no , no...
Wait, wait, wait, hold on.
You know, you have a very strong arm, princess.
Ok, please! Put the monkey down.
- Stay back, or I'll... I'll...
- Please, please, please...
Ah, oh well...allow me to introduce myself:
I'm Prince Naveen.
... of Maldonia.
A prince?
But I didn't wish for any...
Hold on, if you're the prince,then...
then who was that
waltzing with Lottie on the dance floor?
All I know,is one minute I am a prince,
charming and handsome, cutting-a-rug,and the next thing I know,
...I am tripping over these.
Wait, wait, wait...
Wait!
I know this story!
Di Frogie Prutto!
- The Frog Prince?
- Yes, yes, yes...
My mother had the servants
read this to me every night.
Yes, yes...
this is exactly the answer!
You ...
- You must kiss me!
- Excuse me?
You will enjoy it, I guarantee.
All women enjoy the kiss...
of Prince Naveen.
Come, we pucker.
That's new.
Look, I'm sorry.
I'd really like to help you, but I just...
Do not kiss frogs.
Wait a second!
But...On the balcony, you ask me...
- I didn't expect you to answer!
- Oh, but you must kiss me.
Look, besides being unbelievably handsome,
I also happened to come from
a fabulously wealthy family.
Surely, I can offer you some type of reward
or a wish I could grant perhaps...
Yes?
Just...
- One kiss?
- Just one.
Unless you beg for more.
Ok Tiana, you can do this...
Just a little kiss, just a little kiss.
Ok!
You don't look there much different.
But how did you get way up there?
And how did I get way down here,in all this!
- Easy princess, do not panic.
- What did you do to me?
- I...I'm green and I'm...and I'm slimy!
- No, no, no ...
- This is not slime.
- What?
You're secreting mucus.
Stella!
Get that frogs!
- Run!
- I can't run, I'm a frog.
Then hop!
Calm boy, calm you monster dog!
En garde!
Look out! Get out of the way.
- Where are we going?
- Excuse me!
- I can't see a thing.
- Me neither, can I?
- Wait, Stella...
- Get up!
- Stella, it's me, Tiana!
- Tiana?
Stella just talked to me!
The dog just spoke to me!
You know, if you are going to let
every little thing bother you...
It's going to be  very long night!
Oh dear?
- You are so quiet?
- You let him go!
The poor dear frog was scarfing , so
I loosened the lid, and....
How do I ever get tangled
up in all this voodoo madness?
I can't get through with this.
- You wear this ...this ghostly flinger!
- Amulet!
Anything happens to this ...
I'm gonna need...
Fun fact about voodoo, Larry.
Can counter a thing for myself.
Besides ... you and I both know the
real power in this world ain't magic.
It's money.
Lots of it.
- It's true.
- Aren't you tired of living on a smidgens,
While all those fat cats in their fancy cars
don't give you so much of a sideway's glance ?
Yes...
I am.
All you got to do is marry
Big Daddy's little princess ...
And we will splittin' that juicy
La Bouff fortune right down in the middle.
Sixty-forty
like i said.
But ...
- What about Naveen?
- You little slip-up...
We will be a minor bump in the road,
so long as we got
the prince's blood in this.
Voodoo?
You mean to tell me this all happened
because you were messing with the Shadow Man?
He was very charismatic!
It serves me right for wishing on stars.
The only way to get what you want in this
world is through hard work.
Hard work?
Why... why would a princess
need to work hard?
Huh? Oh, I'm not a princess.
I'm a waitress.
A waitress? Well no wonder the kiss
did not work!
You lied to me!
- I...I never said I was a princess.
- You never said you were a w... a waitress!
You were wearing a crown.
It was a costume party,
- You spoiled little rich boy.
- Oh, oh yes, oh ye?
Well, the egg is on your face, alright,
because I do not have any riches!
- What?
- I am completely broke.
You said ...
- You were fabulously wealthy!
- No, no, no.
My parents are fabulously wealthy.
But they cut me off for being a...
Leech! Leech!
You're broke, and you had
the gall to call me a liar?
It was not a lie!
I fully inte...Aaah!
I fully intend to be rich again!
Once I marry Miss Charlotte La Bouff'
and she will help me!
- You a prince?
- obviously!
She'll help you!
All right then.
Once you two are married,
you are gonna keep your promise
- and get me my restaurant, right?
- Whoa, oh, not so fast.
I made that promise to a beautiful princess,
not a cranky wai...
Why are those logs moving?
Those aren't logs!
I got glimpse on a big one.
- C'mon, come here!
- Come here you tasty one mussel!
Where did they go?
Lower the vine.
Find your own tree.
- There he is.
- I've seen him! I've seen him!
Okay, help me get out of this swamp and once
I married Charlotte, I shall get you your restaurant.
You gonna taste so good you
waisted invaluable rat!
Quick, quick, pull me up!
You can hop ...
-but you can't hide.
-We got all night!
Well,waitress, looks like
we going to be here for a while.
So we may as well get ...
comfortable.
Take your slimes away from me.
I've told you ...
It is not slime!
It is mucus.
Rise and shine, Sleeping Beauty.
Gators are gone.
We got to get back to New Orleans ...
And undo this mess you got us into.
I was not the one  parading around
with your phony baloney tiara.
Music de paddle bile.
Could use a little help!
I will play a little louder.
How about a little less piggin' and a ...
I know that tune!
Dippermouth Blues.
- Play it, brother!
- Where you've been all my life?!
- Where did you learn to play like that?
Well, the Bajou's is
the best jazz school in the world.
All the greats play the riverboats.
Oh, Louis give anything to be up there
jammin’ with the big boys.
- So why don't you?
- Oh, I tried once.
It didn't end well.
It is been a real pleasure meetin' you, Louis.
And thank you for coming and
for not eatin' us.
We best be on our way.
Where are you goin'?
- To find somebody to break the spell.
- What spell?
Brace yourself, my skilly friend,
We are not frogs ...
- We are humans.
- What?
You are serious?
I am Naveen, Prince of Maldonia.
And she is Tiana, the waitress.
Do not kiss her.
Now just a second.
This corny here got himself turned
into a frog by a voodoo man and now ...
Voodoo? Like the kind Mama Odie do.
- Mama, hoodie ?
- Mama Odie.
She is the voodoo queen of the Bajou.
She got magic and spells
of kind a voodoo .
Could you take us to her?
To the deepest, darkest
part of a Bayou??
Facing raser sharks, prick ambushers,
and trappers, and hunters with guns?
No.
Watch and learn.
Louis, that's to bad we can not
help you with your dream.
If only you were smaller...
less toothy.
You can play jazz to adoring crowd
without scaring them.
Anyway, enjoy your loneliness, my friend!
Abenaza.
Cute, but it's not gonna...
Hey guys, I just had me
a crazy idea.
What about if I ask Mama Odie
to turn me human?
Louis, you are a genius.
Hallelujah!
If I were a human being
I'd head straight for New Orleans
and I'd blow this horn
so hot and strong
like no one they'd ever seen
Louis Armstrong, Mister Sydney Bechet
All the boys gonna step aside
when they hear this old Alligator play
Listen!
When I'm human
as I hope to be
I'm gonna blow this horn
till the cows come home
and everyone's gonna bow down to me!
Thank you! Thank you!
Aw, thank you! I love you too baby!
When I'm myself again
I want just the life I had
Aye
that doesn't sound too bad
a redhead on my left arm
a brunette on my right
a blonde or two to hold a candle
that seem just about right
Eh, Louis?
Life is short
when you're done, you're done
we're on this Earth to have some fun
- and that's the way things are
- Say it, brother!
When I'm human,
and I'm gonna be
I'm gonna tear it up like I did before
that's a royal guarantee
You are getting married!
All right. I just have to leave a
string of broken hearts behind me.
Your modesty becomes you
and your sense of responsibility
I worked hard for everything I got
and that's the way it's supposed to be
When I'm a human being
at least I'll act like one
if you do your best
each and every day
good things are sure to come your way
What you give is what you get!
My daddy said that
and now I'll never forget
and I amend it to you
When we're human
and we're gonna be
I'm gonna blow my horn!
I'm gonna live the high life!
I'm gonna do my best
to take my place in the sun
When we're human!
Oh, Prince Naveen, dear.
I am positively mortified you had
to endure that frog fiasco last night.
Well, when you’re next in line for the throne,
you’re poised like a panther,
ready to expect the unexpected.
- Y-your ear?
- What?
Oh, there's pesky mosquitoes...
everywhere.
Get in here!
Please, Miss Charlotte, I can no longer
ignore the throbbing of my...
Heart.
Even though our time together's been brief,
it's been heavenly.
Let it...Place, Prince Naveen,
You got me blushin' 'til I...
Would you do me the honor of becoming
Princess of Maldonia?
Are you serious?
As the plague.
Yes!
Oh, I most definitely will marry you!
Oh, there's so much to plan!
The guest list! The dress! The music!
The flowers! The shoes!
We're gonna have ourselves
a Mardi Gras weddin'.
No!
What we do now?
Because somebody let
our frog prince go, Larry ...
I'm reduced to ask for help from
my friends on the other side.
- Now, that restaurant of yours,is it gonna have étouffée?
- Jambalaya, gumbo ...It's gonna have it all!
- It's gonna have it all!
- I always wanted to try red beans and rice,
- Muffulettas, po' boys...
- Stop Louis.
You two are making me so very hungry.
Interesting.
What are you doing?
You are frightening the food.
This is harder than it looks.
What? Oh, no!
No, no, no!
There is no way I'm kissing a frog
and eating a bug on the same day. .
- Hello
- What are you doin'?
- Stop moving!
- You are making this very difficult.
- Y'all found anything to eat yet, ah?
Oh, my!
Hang on. Old Louis gotta comin'.
No, no, no, no ...
How's that?
This could be a little better.
You know what this needs? A shaft stick!
Be right back!
- This is all your fault!
- My fault... my fault ...
Let me tell you something.I was...
Well, look at you!
Girl, I guess you and your boyfriend
got a little carried away, am I right, am I right?
- No, no, no,that's not possible!
- ... I am the prince of Maldonia!
Let me shine a little light on the situation.
'cuse me. One more time now.
That's cool.
Oh, it's ok baby, I'm not gonna explode me.
I ain't no fire cracka!
Got my big butt roundness.
Right. Women like a man
with big back porch.
Oh you know...
You are done this a real goof of somethin'.
Nobody's going to help?
- Oh, dear!
- Hang on, cap'.
I'm just..
Get the noise comin' out.
I'll catch the fish. Get one, get two.
Aroun' a  fishing time
‘Bout time I introduce myself.
My name Raymond,
but everybody call me Ray..
Pardon me, but your accent...
It's funny, you know?
Ok Jimbrah'.
Born branded the Bayou.
You must be a new around here, ah ?
Actually, we're from the place ...
Far, far away from this world.
Go to bed. Y'all from Shreveport ?
No, no, no.
We are people!
The prince charming here got himself turned
into a frog by a voodoo witch doctor.
Well, there you go.
And we are on a way to Mama Odie's,
we think maybe she could...
Mama Odie?
You are headin' the wrong direction,cher.
Now what kinda chucklehead told
y’all to go thisa way?
I found the stick!
Louis ...
Ray here says you've been taking us
in the wrong direction.
I was ...listen,
I was confused by the topography and...
The geography and choreography.
Fist rule the Bayou.Never take
the rescue from a gator.
Me and my relations those
will help you yard the way.
Achedanza! (Cool).
Cousin Randy,You are ready for
the Bayou Zydeco.
Ready when you are, cousin Ray!
Alright, Lulu!
Let's get to it, darling!
Come on, cher!
Just follow the bouncing butt!.
We're gonna take ya down, We're gonna take ya down
We're gonna take ya all the way down.
We're gonna take ya all the way.
Goin' down the bayou!
Taking ya all the way!
We got the whole family!
There goes Mimi!
Cousin Boudreau!
Grandma Ma,
you're light on!
We all gon' pool together
Down here that's how we do!
Me for them, and them for me,
We all be there for you!
We're gonna take ya, We're gonna take ya
We're gonna take ya all the way down
We know where yer going and we're going with you
Taking you all the way
Goin' down the bayou!
Take ya all....
Yeah, you know!
Come on y'all! Keep that life flowin',
and them lights a'glowin!Yeah,you're right!
Friends, I know I'm in hack to
you all pretty deep already,
but it seems or little froggy prince lost his way.
And I need your generous assistance getting him back.
Hahaha, I hear you.Now, what's in it for you?
Well...
As soon as I dispose of "Big Daddy" La Bouff,
then I'm gonna run this town.
I'll have the entire city of New Orleans
in the palm of my hand.
And you'll have all the wayward souls
your dark little hearts desire.
You all love that, don't you?
So, we got ourselves a deal?
Hahaha! Now we're cooking!
We're gonna find ourselves a frog.
Search everywhere: The bayou, the quarter...
bring him to me alive.
I need his heart pumping...
For now.
Allez, tout de suite!
- Ray will take you the rest of way!
- Nice meetin' you all!
- Bye, Bye pooky!
- Adieu, bye, bye amis.
And don't forget to tell Angela
that Ray said Bonjour!
- That's your girl?
- Oh, no, no, no ...
- My girl...does Evangeline.
- Evangeline?
She is the most prettiest
butterfly ever did glow.
You know, I talk to Evangeline
almost every night.
She is kind of shy,not say much.
But I know in my heart
someday we gonna be together.
- Oh, that's so sweet.
- Yes, so sweet ...
Just do not settle down so quickly, friend.
There are plenty of fireflies
in this world.
What?
Prick ambushers got me ...
Get down, get down!
Darkness ... it's closin' in.
I'm so cold.
Will you hold still, big baby?
I touched you.
Oh, take a look at that two jumpers.
I can taste the frog legs already...
With a sauce picante, right Pa?
Will you keep quiet!
Oh, my thought is exactly the same.
It's time to catch up some frogs.
You know, waitress, I finally
figured out what is wrong with you.
- Have you, now?
- You do not know how to have fun.
There. Somebody had to say it.
Thank you, 'cause I figured out
what your problem is too.
I am... too wonderful?
No, you're a no-count, polandering,
lazy bump on a log.
Ahaha... Killjoy.
- What'd you say?
- Ah, nothing.
- Stick in the mud.
- Listen here, mister.
This stick in the mud has had to
work two jobs her whole life
while you've been sucking on a silver spoon
chasing chamber maids around your...
your ivory tower!
Actually, it's polished marble.
Uh, I got me one, boys!
Get the little one over there.
The hunt was good today, yes indeed?
Hunters with guns!
Look at his big frog legs.
I will mixed them...
Oh, no, no, no.
A bug gotta do what a bug gotta do!
I think I got chipped my favorite tooth.
Here I come, Two Fingers, I'll help.
Pa, we got one.
Be on quiet y'all.
- What happend to yours?
- Shut your preaft, Darnell.
I'm free!
Pa, did you hear that suspicous tide?
Yeah ...
I surely did.
What you two cockin' head...?
Just miss it there.
I will make them dessert legs.
- Come on, go.
Stop.
No, no, no, you idiot, don't shoot.
Watch this.
Missed it!
Get out of way!
These two ain't like no frogs
I've ever seen.
- They're smart.
- And we talk, too.
You alright there, little bud?
Oh, I'm fine...
but your breath done killed me to death!
Would you mind?
I got you cover, brah.
Ah, much obliged, PeeWee.
Now how about ...
The other side.
And we talk too. I like that!
You are secretly funny.
- Not a stick in the mud?
- W-well I was...
- Say it. -Co... - Say it.
- All right... You're not exactly...
- I can't hear you, I'm sorry. What?
- ...a complete stick deep in the mud.
Easy!
I get this one in there, in it,  now hold on.
Sug', I know we got to get to
Mama Odie lingering split but ...
This particuler extract provocation
grant take a while, yeah.
- Oh, poor Louis.
- You know what would make me feel better?
Crawfish snuged in Remoulade Sauce.
- Slow down!
- Got a lil more!
Some banana foster
sprinkled with brollies.
- How about some swamp gumbo?
- That'll do.
Sounds delicious! I'll start with free dinner cocktail
and something to nibble on, while I wait, thanks.
No, no, no, no, Your Royal Highness.
- What's a matter?
- You are gonna to mince this mushrooms.
- To do what?
Mince the mushrooms.
Hop, to it!
- This is ridiculous.
- Are you mincing?
All right ...
Relax.
One!
Step aside, Mister.
Watch ...
And learn.
- All right.
- There you go.
- You know, I never done anything like this before.
- Really?
All right.
But, when you are livin' in a castle
everything is done for you:
all the time they dress you, they feed you,
drive you...
Brush your teeth!
Aw, poor baby.
I admitted it was a charmed life, until the day
my parents cut me off, and suddenly I realized...
I don't know how to do anything.
Well hey ...
You've got to make some descent mushrooms mincer, ok?
- Oh, you think so?
- Keep practicing and I just might hire you.
- Really?
- No.
Come on ...
What was that?!
That was below the frog belt...
You said hello and he said what.
And you said:
Get a ugly face in...
- Anyone for seconds?
- That was magnificient...
You truly have a gift.
Well!
Thank you!
There she is.
The sweetest firefly of all creation.
Envangeline?
I want to meet this girl, where she is?
How can you miss her,
she glows right up there, in front of you.
Look how she lights up the sky
Ma belle Evangeline
Oh, that ain't no firefly, that's a...
So far above me yet I
Know her heart belongs to only me
- J t'adore. - I adore you.
- Je t'aime. - I love you.
-Evangeline
- I'm just translating!
You're my queen of the night
So still, so bright
To someone as beautiful as she
Who loves someone like me
- No, no. I don't dance.
- Love always finds a way, it's true
- I've never danced.
- And I love you Evangeline
- If I can mince, you can dance. - Oooh, yeah!
Love is beautiful
Love is wonderful
Love is everything, do you agree?
Mais oui!
Look how she lights up the sky
I love you, Evangeline
Ah, Lottie's goodness for a heck of a dance partner.
We ...
Best we pushin' on.
- Tiana!
- Naveen!
No, no, no.
Not bad for a 197 year old blind lady.
Now, which one of you naughty kiddy been messing
with the Shadow Man?
We so glad we found you Mama Odie.
Ray and Louis here been tellin' us all about you.
We've been travelling quite a long way.
And you can't imagine what we've been through.And we...
- And we heard that you ...
- Juju!
Come on, over here,
you bad boy.
Give a little sugar now.
You just dooz your mama, don't you?
Good to see you again, Ray.
- How's your grandma Ma?
- Oh, she's fine.
Got in a little trouble for flashing
the neighbours again.
- Ouh! I like that gal's spunk.
- Mama Odie ...
- We don't want to take too much of your time.
- You want some candies?
- No, not really.
- No, no thank you.
Well now, that's too bad. This is a special candy.
- Woulda turn y'all human.
- No, no, no, please.
I'm just messing with y'all.
How on earth did you know that we want to turn back...
- Mama Odie?
- Juju!
Why didn't you tell me my gumbo was burnin'?
You sure this is the right blind voodoo lady
who lives in the boat in the tree in the bayou?
Pretty sure.
- I can't believe this,
got to do everythin' around here.
- Mama Odie, if you ...
- Taste it.
- Well?
- Hit it hard with a couple of shots of Tabasco,
and it's the bee's knees!
Now, can we...
- Juju!
That's got some zydin' to it.
I guess that's what we needed.
Now, you figured out what you need?
It's just like you said, Mama Odie.
We need to be human.
You only got to say she was blankly?
You want to be human ...
But you blind to what you need.
What we want, what we need ...
It's all the same thing, yes?
It's the same thing?
No!
You listen to your Mama now.
Don't matter what you look like
Don't matter what you wear
How many rings you got on your finger
We don't care
- No we don't care
Don't matter where you come from
Don't even matter what you are
A dog, a pig, a cow, a goat
Had 'em all in here
We had 'em all in here
And they all knew what they wanted
What they wanted me to do
I told 'em what they needed
Just like I be telling you
You got to dig a little deeper
Find out who you are
It really ain't that far
When you find out who you are
You'll find out what you need
Blue skies and sunshine guaranteed
You got to dig
- Dig
Prince Froggy is a rich little boy
You wanna be rich again
That ain't gonna make you happy now
Did it make you happy then?
No!
Money ain't got no soul
Money ain't got no heart
All you need is some self-control
Make yourself a brand new start
You got to dig a little deeper
Don't have far to go
Tell the people Mama told you so
Can't tell you what you'll find
Maybe love will grant you peace of mind
Dig a little deeper and you'll know
- Miss Froggy,
- Ma'am ?
- Might I have a word?
- Yes, Ma'am.
You's a hard one,
that's what I heard
Your daddy was a loving man
Family through and through
You your daddy's daughter
What he had in him you got in you
You got to dig a little deeper
For you it's gonna be tough
You ain't dug near far enough
Dig down deep inside yourself
You'll find out what you need
Blue skies and sunshine guaranteed
Open up the windows
Let in the light children
Blue skies and sunshine
Guaranteed...
Well, Miss Froggy?
Do you understand what you need now, child?
Yes! I do, Mama Odie.
I need to dig a little deeper and work
even harder to get my restaurant.
All right y'all, one more time.
It don't matter what you look like
It don't...
Nobody goin' to sing with Ray?
Okay.
Well, if you swell on bein' human
there's only one way.
Gumbo, gumbo in the pot,
We need a precious.
What we got?!
- Lottie? But she is not a princess!
- Oh, shut and look at gumbo!
That's right ... Big Daddy
is king of Mardi Gras parade.
So, that makes Lottie...
- A princess.
- Does that count?
Yes it does, but only 'til midnight,
when Mardi Gras is over.
Hop-Lone, you only got 'til the end
to got that princess to kiss you.
Once she does ...
- You both turnin' human.
- Midnight?
- That doesn't give us much time at all.
- What about me, Mama?
I want to be human too,
so I can play jazz with the big boys.
I want fingers, and toes, and a belly button,
Not the kind that sticks out, but the kind that goes in…
Big Jaws, you dig little deeper,
you'll find everythin' you need.
C'mon, C'mon, C'mon...
You got a river to run here, darling.
- Y'all best get to swimmin'.
- Wait...
I've got a better idea.
They got guns!
Bam, that is one Killer Diller costume.
Hey dale, can you blow that horn?
- Come on, stay in with us.
- We play on Mardi Gras.
We can miss this.
Little Louis gonna finally play with the big boys.
Naveen, you comin'?
I'll catch up with you later.
Oh, Evangeline ... why I can't just look
Tiana in the eyes and say:
I will do whatever it takes
to make all your dreams come true, because ...
Because I love you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, cap'.
You are makin' googoo eyes on my girl?
Got you!
I will make some shoes out of you.
Ray, I'm not in love with Evangeline
I am in love with Tiana.
- I knew it, I knew it, I knew it. You come here, you...
- I can't no longer marry Miss Charlotte La Bouff.
- You will be so happy together.
- I will find another way to get Tiana a restaurant.
- You coulda have a cute, little ted frog.
- I'll get job, maybe two.
- Maybe three?
- I can't wait to tell her.
- No, no, no. I must tell her. Alone.
- Right, you bet...
- Where are you taking me?
- Oh, I just...
wanted to show you little something to
celebrate our last night together as frogs.
Oh... All my years.
No one's ever done anything like this for me.
I - it is too much, isn't it? Um...
- Thank you, Bow.
- I thought it was a nice touch.
Pretend you did not see that.
Please, please sit down.
- What's this?
- Ta-da!
- You minced!
- I did!
You have had quite an influence on me.
Which is amazing because I have dated
thousands of women and...
No, like two, three... just other women!
A-and anyway, you could not be more different!
You know, you are - you are practically,
one of the guys!
No no no! You are not a guy!
Let me begin again! Uh...
Ha... I am not myself tonight. Tiana!
Sorry, that was loud.
This is a disaster.
No, it's cute.
- Tiana ... I ...
- There it is!
Your restaurant?
Oh, can you just picture it?
All lit up like the Fourth of July.
Yes, jazz pouring out from every window.
- It should be elegant.
- You should keep it loose, don't get it let
Swing.
- You know good ukulele players.
- Really? You let me perform?
I'll talk to the owner ...
Owner says...yes.
Folks are gonna be comin' together from all
walks of life just to get a taste of our food.
Our food?
Oh no, no, no. My Daddy...
He always wanted open this restaurant.
He died before he could see it happened.
But tomorrow ... with your help.
Our dreams are finally comin' true.
- Tomorrow?
- If I don't deliver that money first thing tomorrow,
I lose this place forever.
Tiana, I love ...
The way you light up
when you talk about your dream.
A dream that it is so beautiful
I ...
I promise ...
I will do whatever it takes to make it come true.
Port of New Orleans.
All ashore.
I. .. I'll go run up the boys.
Evangeline ...
I've always been so sure about what i wanted.
But now ...
What do I do?
Please tell me.
Prince Naveen, darlin'.
You better hurry up.
Don't wanna be late for
our Mardi Gras weddin'.
Getting dressed
Just a few moments, my dear Charlotte.
Okay, honeylame.
We'll been waitin' in the packwood.
Daddy, start the car!
Oh, heavens ... I'm doomed.
No, Larry. I'm the one who's doomed.
Less me get that frog's blood...
No!
We are back in business, boys.
Get your filthy hands off me.
Lawrence?
Hold still, Your Eminence.
Ray
Haven't seen Naveen?
- Look at you, where's the ring at?
- What are you talking about?
Well, if captain say nothing
I ain't gonna say nothing.
Because old Ray sealed up tight as a drum
you ain't got nothin' out of me, no!
- Ray?
- Okay, captain ain't gonna marry Charlotte
he gonna marry you.
soon as he get himself kissed, and you
both turn human, he go find a job,
get you that restaurant.
- I said too much, didn't I?
- You said just enough, Ray!
Thank you, Evangeline.
He was trying to propose,
that's what all that fun was about.
And here I thought, all he wanted
was to marry a rich girl.
Sug', what are we looking for in here?
You just keep your eyes at one of
of the biggest godies float
with a Mardi Gras princess
about to kissed herself a ...a frog.
Dear beloved, we are gathered here
tonight in this fine celebration
to join together this prince and
this young woman in holy matrimony.
Oh, no, this can't be right, darlin'.
Then how you can still be a frog?
Mama Odie...she's...
I know what we've seen with our eyes but...
If we just go back there
we gonna find that your fairy tale come true.
Just because you wish for somethin',
doesn't make it true.
- It's like my Evangeline always said to me ...
- Evangeline is nothing but a star, Ray!
A big ball of hot air a million miles from here.
Open your eyes now!
Before you get hurted.
She's just big in a broken heart...
That's all it is.
Come on Evangeline.
We gonna show sug' the truth.
If any of you, object to the union
of this two people
speak now or forever hold your plea.
Me, Me, I object.
Do you, Prince Naveen, take
Charlotte to be your wife ...
Cap, what are you doing, son?
...as long as you both shall live?
What? I do ...
Yes, I'm for it.
Is that you, cap?
Ray, get me out of this box!
I can't hear you,
I'll go get you out of this box.
...as long as you both shall live?
Oh, I do.
Then so, by the power invested in me
by the state of Louisiana
I now pronounce you ...
Man and. ..
Prince Naveen!
- Goodness gracious! Are you all right?
- I just need a moment to compose myself.
Cheese and crackers!
Lawrence, why are you doing this?
It's payback for all those years of...
- Humiliation.
- Get your royal a...
back on that wedding cake
and finish this deal.
What is he doing?
Stop him!
I got him.
He got me too!
- Gimme that!
- Stay on the side!
Ray?
Hey, why did you stop?
- Sug'? Sug'?
- Ray?
This proves what we saw
ain't what we thought we saw.
- What is this?
- It's voodoo, hydeco?
The Shadow Man, he's been usin' voodoo...
You can't let Shadow Man get this, no matter what.
Now run girl, run!
Do not make me light my butt.
I got lightin' on me.
Come here, you!
Ok,come!
Ray!
What ...
Ray?
Back off! Or I'm gonna break this
into a million pieces.
Naveen?
Now, isn't this whole life better than hoppin'
around bayou for the rest of your life??
Shadow Man?
Got a head to you, Tiana.
When you dream, you dream big.
Just look at this place! Gonna be the crown
jewel of the cursancy.
And all you got to do,
to make this reality
It's handle that little talisman of mine.
No.
This-this is not right.
Come on, darlin'?
Think of everything you sacrificed.
- Girl, all you ever do is work.
- I told y'all she wouldn't come.
Think of all those maecenas who doubted you.
- You ain't never gonna get enough for the dang payment.
- Woman of your background, you better off will y'all.
And don't forget your poor Daddy.
- Now, that was one hard working man.
- See you tomorrow, James!
Double, sometimes triple shifts.
Never let know how bone tired,
beat darlin' really was.
- Daddy!
- Hey, babby cakes.
Shame on that hard work, didn't amount
much more than a busted up, old gumbo pot.
And a dream that never get off the back porch.
But you ...
You can give your poor Daddy
everything he ever wanted.
Come on, Tiana.
You're almost there.
My Daddy never did get what he wanted.
But he had what he needed.
He had love.
- Never lost a sight what was really important.
- Easy with that! Careful!
And neither will I.
Y'all should've taken my deal.
Now you will spend the rest of your life
bein' a slimy little frog!
I got news for you, Shadow Man!
It's not slime, it's mucus!
No! No!
How am I ever gonna pay back my debt?!
- Friends!
- Are you ready?
- No! I'm not ready at all! In fact, I got lots more plans!
This is just a minor setback in a major operation!
As soon as I whip up another spell,
we'll be back in business!
I still got that froggy prince locked away!
I just need a little more time.
No! No, please, no!
Just a little more time!
I promise I'll pay y'all back! I promise!
Prince! Prince Naveen
Your shini', retirin' bride,
completely is gettin' anxiety.
Hello, darling!
Miss La Bouff
Please down here.
Let me to introduce myself.
I am the real Prince Naveen!
Of Maldonia.
Did you say prince?
- Boys, drag this maggot down to the Parish prison.
- I'm completely innocent.
The Shadow Man bamboozled me.
Goodness gracious!
This is so much to absorb.
Let me see if I got this right.
If I kiss you before midnight,
you and Tiana will turn human again,
and then we gonna get ourselves married
and live happily ever after!
- The end!
- Yeah, more or less.
But remember, you must give Tiana all
the money she requires for her restaurant.
Because Tiana ...
She is my Evangeline.
Anything you want, sugar.
Pucker up, buttercup!
- Wait!
- Tiana?
- Don't do this.
I have to do this and we are running out of time!
- I won't let you!
- It's the only way to get you your dream!
My dream?
My dream wouldn't be complete...
Without you in it.
I love you, Naveen.
- Warts and all?
- Warts and all.
All my life, I read about true love and fairytales, and...
Tia, you found it!
I'll kiss him! For you, honey!
No marriage required.
Oh my word!
M-maybe that ol' clock's a little fast!
I'm so sorry!
Tiana! Naveen!
Louis, what is it?
- Shadow Man laid poor Ray low!
- Ray?
He's hurtin' awful bad.
Hey, sug'!
- How come, y'all still ...
- We are stayin' frogs, Ray.
And we are stayin' together.
Oh, I like that very much.
Evangeline like that too.
So, by the power invested in me ...
I now pronounce you frog and wife.
Get to it, Hop Lone,
and give your lovely bride some sugar.
Congratulations!
This gonna be good!
Like I told y'all, kissing a princess
brake the spell.
Once you became my wife,
that made you ...
A princess.
You just kissed yourself a princess!
And I'm about to do it again!
In the South Land there's
A city
Way down on the river
Where the women are very pretty
And all the men deliver
They got music
It's always playin'
Start in the day time, go all through the night
When you hear that music playin'
Hear what I'm saying and make it feel alright
Who would've thought the prince
woulda had a younger brother.
- How old did you say you were?
- I'm six and a half.
Well, I waited this long.
Grab somebody, come on down
Bring your paintbrush, we're painting the town
There's some sweetness going around
Dreams do come true in New Orleans.
By radojka, january 2010
WWW.subscene.com